Trichy, Tamil Nadu – 620002 +91-9384862265 | <u>sendmsq2siva@qmail.com</u> https://r35007.qithub.io/Siva Profile

Summary

Frontend developer with over 7 years of experience in building responsive, user-friendly websites and applications. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, typescript, strong problem-solving and debugging skills and modern frameworks such as React and Angular. Seeking a challenging role to continue learning and growing as a developer.

Experience

7+ Years

Technical Anchor - SG7

May 2023 - Present

Ford Motor Company

Currently working as a Project lead in the Ford Motor Company. Experienced in complete architecture of a component library creation and deployment. Have also touched AEM (Adobe Experience Manager) and familiar with MFE (Micro Front end) Applications.

Software Engineering III

Dec 2019 - May 2023

Verizon

3.3 years of experience as a frontend developer at Verizon. Experienced in full project lifecycle and automated testing using Cypress and Jest. Skilled in platform hardening and quality assurance.

Software Engineering

Apr 2017 – Dec 2019

Bounteous (Lister Technologies)

2.8 years of experience as a frontend, full stack, and UI/UX developer. Gained a lot of knowledge and experience, and explored new technologies. Great company for a fresher to work with and enriched my knowledge and experience.

Education

Master of Computer Applications – MCA

Apr 2017

Bishop Heber College, Trichy, Tamil Nadu

Course: 2 Years | CGPA: 78.9%

Bachelor of Computer Science - BSc CS

Apr 2015

Apr 2012

St Joseph College, Trichy, Tamil Nadu

Course: 3 Years | CGPA: 59.96%

Higher Secondary Certification - HSC

Sri Renga Matriculation, Trichy, Tamil Nadu

CGPA: 64.83%

Secondary Level School Certification - SSLC

Apr 2012

Sri Renga Matriculation, Trichy, Tamil Nadu

CGPA: 72.2%

Project Links

GitHub - https://github.com/R35007

NPM - https://www.npmjs.com/settings/r35007/packages

VS Code Extension - https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/publishers/Thinker

Skillset

Programming and Languages

- JavaScript 90%
- Typescript 90%

Frameworks and Library

- React
- Angular
- NodeJS
- Next JS
- MFE
- Jest
- Cypress
- Bootstrap
- JQuery
- Single SPA

Tools and Technologies

- HTML
- CSS
- LESS/SASS
- JIRA
- GIT
- Photoshop
- Figma
- G CloudCI/CD
- AEM

Published

Node Packages

- @r35007/mock-server
- fs-props

VS Code Extensions

- Sort JSON 19K downloads
- Font Awesome 11K downloads
- Data Size Count 9K downloads
- Create App 7K downloads
- Mock Server 7K downloads

Hobbies

- Playing Chess
- Watching drams and movies
- Gaming
- Personal projects

Projects

Universal Component Library

May 2023 - Present

- This is a common universal react library components that connects with AEM to author component props.
- This Application contains two themes and also renders in a server-side rendering using assembler platform
- I'm working as a Project lead in offshore. I take care of customer onboarding, development and deployment of this library
- I also take care of platform hardening like writing testcases, sonar cube and ES Lint checks, performance and code optimization, code quality and accessibility of the components.

Company: Ford Motor Company

Technologies: ReactJS, Server-side rendering, Singe SPA, Styled Components, Theming, NodeJS, AEM, JAVA, Jest,

Cypress, Tekton pipeline, GitHub Actions

Team Size: 50+ Customers: 1000+

Digital Sales

Mar 2022 - May 2023

• Worked on digital sales page for mobile phones and tablets with Verizon 5G network.

• Led checkout flow for users to select devices, fill out personal and card details, and place orders.

Company: Verizon

Technologies: ReactJS, NodeJS, Java Spring boot, Material UI, Jest, Cypress Automation, husky, Mock Server

Team Size: 100+

Decommission Equipment

Mar 2021 – Mar 2022

- An Ionic angular app to power up or decommission the router connection.
- Also in parallel has a react app to create a internal ticket to admin to decommission the connection.
- This is an internal app used by the network admins to assign or remove router connection.

Company: Verizon

Technologies: React, Angular11, Ionic Material UI, Mock Server, Java Spring boot, NodeJS

Team Size: 50+

Virtual Network System Protocol - VNSP

Mar 2020 - Mar 2021

• A React app to allocate or configure bandwidth for the specific customer.

Company: Verizon

Technologies: React, NodeJS, bootstrap, Mock Server, Java Spring boot

Team Size: 7+

Canvas Application

Dec 2019 - Mar 2020

• A Task management tool which helps to assign, suspend task etc... for the internal purpose.

Company: Verizon

Technologies: Angular 7, NodeJS, bootstrap, JSON Server, Java Spring boot

Team Size: 5+

Ace Tool

Apr 2019 - Dec 2019

• It is an import and export tool to transfer data between JSON to google sheet and vice versa.

• The content author provides the content in the google sheet which will then converted to a JSON object to run the online education tool.

Company: Lister Technologies

Client: An American Research and Development Team of Lexia group of companies

Technologies: React, Typescript, Electron, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Google App Script

Team Size: 10+

Incentive Pay Management

Jan 2018 - Apr 2019

• A tool to manage the incentive pay for the customers across different regions.

• The region admin can configure different constraints for their legacy customer like increasing the incentive per hour basis or by speed basis.

Company: Lister Technologies

Client: An American Retailing Company - Kroger

Technologies: Angular 7, bootstrap, JSON Server, MongoDB, Java Spring boot, Prime Ng, Chart JS, Dashboards, PDF

Export, Report Generation.

Team Size: 15+

UI / UX Development

Apr 2017 - Jan 2018

• Build a standard Email Templates for different clients which is compatible for all different browsers.

Company: Lister Technologies

Client: Lenovo, Perri cone, Maybelline etc...

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Photoshop, Invision, Bootstrap, jQuery.

Team Size: 7+